<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on Type Phase</title>
    <link>https://www.amirkurtovic.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on Type Phase</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 11:18:31 -0600</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="https://www.amirkurtovic.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>There is no magic, and you should explicitly acknowledge the fact</title>
      <link>https://www.amirkurtovic.com/posts/on-the-lack-of-magic/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2020 11:18:31 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.amirkurtovic.com/posts/on-the-lack-of-magic/</guid>
      <description>Technology is the application of scientific knowledge to produce practical results. Magic is the use of mysterious or mystical forces to achieve supernatural results. In other words, they are opposites.
Yet too often in common parlance, we conflate the two. Apps promise to wow us with &amp;ldquo;magical&amp;rdquo; user experiences. Pundits talk about algorithms wielded like &amp;ldquo;magic spells&amp;rdquo; by modern-day wizards, often to much financial benefit. AI startups promise machine learning models that give &amp;ldquo;magical insights&amp;rdquo; into the inner workings of your company.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>2020 Project: Building a depth sensing vision system from scratch</title>
      <link>https://www.amirkurtovic.com/posts/building-depth-sensing-vision-system/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 20:30:22 -0600</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://www.amirkurtovic.com/posts/building-depth-sensing-vision-system/</guid>
      <description>I&#39;m starting out 2020 with a plan to be a little more rigorous about how I approach my side projects. That includes publicly writing about the details of what I&#39;m working on to both share what I&#39;ve learned and also to hold myself somewhat accountable.
With that being said, some of my general goals for 2020 include:
 Getting more experience with computer vision applications to balance my machine learning knowledge, which up to this point has mostly focused on natural language applications Gaining better understanding of the process involved in building custom electronics and hardware Re-visiting a failed side project from 2018 (more on that below)  My 2020 project is to build a cheap camera-based depth sensing system that can create detailed 3D point clouds, accurately measure distance, detect motion and do simple object identification and classification.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>